<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>SPV</title><link href="http://spv.me/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://spv.me/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://spv.me/</id><updated>2015-08-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>Hello World!</title><link href="http://spv.me/posts/hello-world/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-08-12T00:00:00+05:30</updated><author><name>SPV</name></author><id>tag:spv.me,2015-08-12:posts/hello-world/</id><summary type="html">&lt;!--
abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyzabcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyzabcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyz
--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the first post on my blog.
For a long time, I wanted to have a blog to document stuff so that
I could refer back to them later. Back then in 2010, I looked at Blogger,
Wordpress and Tumblr. I did not like them as I had very limited 
control over the&amp;nbsp;design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Static Site Generators and Github hosting means I can have all the freedom
at zero cost. There is no dearth of Static site generators these days.
I have tried &lt;a href="http://getpelican.com/"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="http://jekyllrb.com"&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;,
&lt;a href="http://jaspervdj.be/hakyll/"&gt;Hakyll&lt;/a&gt; and feel pelican suits me&amp;nbsp;well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I liked Jekyll a lot, especially the fact that I can directly push markdown to
my repo rather than the html generated from markdown. However, I never used Ruby.
So I did not want to install Ruby, Jekyll and its many dependencies on my
computer just for&amp;nbsp;blogging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In December 2014, when I was around half way through Learn You A Haskell book,
I wanted a project to apply my newly acquired haskell knowledge. That&amp;#8217;s how I
stumbled on &lt;a href="http://jaspervdj.be/hakyll/"&gt;Hakyll&lt;/a&gt;. put me in a situation where I was not
able to reproduce the setup from one computer to another. Also I am not as
comfortable with Haskell as I am with Python.
Pelican&amp;#8217;s stability also should help me concentrate on writing the content.
Eventually I came back to Pelican which I tried&amp;nbsp;first.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>